Jesse Ortiz

(661) 661-860-7705 Jessebryan1297@gmail.com 3616 Drysdale Dr Lancaster, CA 93535

SUMMARY

Energetic, reliable, team player with over 3 years' experience in Aerospace as an Aircraft Mechanic and a Manufacturing Engineer. Proven ability to take on new challenges as a fast learner effectively working with Aircraft structures, Composites, Hydraulics, Electrical, and Augmented Reality Manufacturing Technology. Ability to communicate across different organizations and teams to achieve goals. Experience successfully working in fast paced environments.

SKILLS

- CAD software: CPLM, NX, CATIA
- Experience in production
- HoloLens 2 Devices

- Microsoft Office
- Lean management & six sigma
- Technical writing

- Manufacturing Software: MES
- Communication skills
- Blueprint reading

EXPERIENCE

01/2022 – Present Associate Manufacturing Systems Engineer, Northrop Grumman | Palmdale, CA

- Received BRAVO award for my work to meet milestones with Augmented Reality.
- Review and interpret Blueprints, Engineering Orders, and 3D models to create work instructions.
- Work with Augmented Reality Technology to improve manufacturing processes.
- Interface/communicate with multiple levels of leadership, Engineering, clients, and vendors to meet goals.
- Support and provide demonstrations of AR technology to Frontline leadership, Engineering Organizations, multiple programs, Space sector, and Defense sector.
- Work projects concurrently across multiple programs while meeting customer requirements/expectations
- Software's used: NX, CPLM, CATIA, VAS, Vis Pro, Create 2, Pixyz Studio.
- Interface with shop floor mechanics, leads, and liaison ME to improve processes and reduce build time.

06/2019 – 01/2022 Aircraft Mechanic, Northrop Grumman | Palmdale, CA

- Experience and certification in Structures, Composites, Electrical and Systems.
- Read and interpret blueprints
- Fabrication of metallic and composite structures using methods including precision drilling and countersinking
- •Working with composites using wet layups, pre preg material, core materials, vacuum bagging schedule, epoxies, and resins
- Assemble, install and Perform maintenance of hydraulic systems.
- •Install electrical components

05/2016 – 05/2019 Sheriff Cadet, Antelope Valley College | Lancaster, CA

•job functions - safety services, Law enforcement police dispatch operations, public relations, Investigation assistance.

EDUCATION

07/2022 – Present Master of Science: Software Development, Boston University | Boston, MA

Graduated 12/2021 Bachelor of Science: Airframe Manufacturing Technology, Antelope Valley College | Lancaster, CA

Completed 06/2019 Certificate: Aircraft Fabrication and Assembly, Antelope Valley College | Lancaster, CA